mychaletfinder.com 2019-01-05

# Privacy Policy - My Chalet Finder

### Introduction

Continental Traveller Limited and its operating platforms such as this website, MyChaletFinder.com, are committed to protecting your privacy and assuring the confidentiality of your data. This policy explains how and for what purposes we use the information collected about you via MyChaletFinder.com (referred to below as "this website") and follows the rules and suggestions contained within the General Data Protection Regulation 2018 ("GDPR"). Please read this privacy policy carefully. By using this website and any services we offer via this website, you are agreeing to be bound by this policy in respect of the information collected about you via this website.

Data Protection law says that we can use personal data only if we have a proper reason to do so. This includes sharing it outside MyChaletFinder.com. The law says we must have one or more of these reasons:

  * To fulfil a contract we have with you
  * When it's our legal duty
  * When it's in our legitimate interest
  * When you consent to it

A legitimate interest is when we have a legitimate business or commercial reason to use your information. But even then, it must not unfairly go against what is right and best for you. If we rely on our legitimate interest, we will tell you what that is.

Below is a list of all the ways that we may use your personal data, and which of the reasons we rely on to do so. Our legitimate interests are also below.

### Serving our customers

What we use your personal data for:

  * To deliver our products and services
  * To manage our relationship with you or your business
  * To develop new ways to meet our customers’ needs and to grow our business
  * To develop and carry out future marketing activities such as via newsletters where you choose to opt-in
  * To study how our customers use our products and services
  * For potential future marketing of our products and services

Our reasons:

  * Your consent
  * Fulfilling contracts
  * Our legitimate interests
  * Our legal duty

Our legitimate interests:

  * Keeping our records up to date
  * Working out which of our products and services may interest you and telling you about them
  * Developing products and services, and what we charge for them
  * Defining types of customers for new products and services
  * Seeking your consent when we need it to contact you
  * As an active customer to keep you informed about our latest offers, deals and competitions
  * Being efficient about how we fulfil our legal and contractual duties

### Operating our business effectively

What we use your personal data for:

To run our business in an efficient and proper way. This includes managing our business capability, financial position, communications, corporate governance, planning, and audit.

Our reasons:

  * Our legitimate interests
  * Our legal duty

Our legitimate interests:

  * Complying with regulations that apply to us
  * Being efficient about how we fulfil our legal and contractual duties

### Developing our products and services

What we use your personal data for:

  * To develop and manage our brand, products, and services
  * To manage how we work with other companies that provide products and services to us and our customers
  * To find people who might benefit from using our products and services

Our reasons:

  * Fulfilling contracts
  * Our legitimate interests
  * Our legal duty

Our legitimate interests:

  * Developing products and services, and what we charge for them
  * Defining types of customers for new products and services
  * Being efficient about how we fulfil our legal and contractual duties
  * Complying with regulations that apply to us

When logging on to our website, we collect, process and use the IP address of your terminal as well as other information such as date, time, the called-up page and store this information. This data is not utilised except anonymously for statistical purposes. We only store your personal data like name, physical and postal addresses, telephone number, fax number, eMail address etc. when you give them to us during a booking procedure or if you are advertising a service on the website through, for example, banner adverts or other promoted services such as airport transfers or ski schools.

### Personal information collected

When you visit, register or use the services on this website, you may be asked to provide certain information about yourself, including your name and your contact details. We may also collect information about how you use this website including your searches, the properties and pages you look at, the advertisers or partners you contact and the contents of the emails you send to them. Finally, we may also collect information from any correspondence that you have with us. Collectively, we refer to this as "Your Information".

All of the forms where you might enter personal information on our website have tick box options to enable you to specify your consent (or otherwise) to our use of Your Information. We always use the the most recently submitted form to be your current consent status. If you are a registered user, but not signed in when you submit a form, we won't be able to use your saved settings so will deem your consent choice to be as per the form you submit at the time.

### What happens if you choose not to give us your personal data?

We may need to collect personal data by law, or under the terms of a contract we have with you.

If you choose not to give us this personal data, it may delay or prevent us providing our products or services to you. For example, not providing an email address would prevent us activating your advertising account.

Sometimes we might ask for information that is useful for us to know but is not required by law or a contract. When this is the case, we will make this clear by marking it as optional. You do not have to provide these extra bits of information, and your choice will not prevent us providing you with our products or services.

### How do we use your data for marketing?

We may use your personal data to tell you about our relevant products, competitions and offers. This is what we mean when we talk about ‘marketing’. 

We will send you marketing based on what you tell us about yourself, data we collect when you use our services, and using information from third parties we work with. We use this information to get a view on what we think would interest you the most.

We will only send you marketing messages if we have either your consent or a legitimate interest. This is when we have a legitimate business or commercial reason to use your information that does not unfairly go against what is right and best for you.

You can ask us to stop sending you marketing messages by contacting us at any time by clicking unsubscribe at the bottom of any marketing email or updating your preferences in your online account.

Whatever you choose for marketing, you'll still receive service messages, such as booking confirmations.

### Other Potential Uses Your Information

The company may use ‘Cookies’ in the future to make the use of the website easier. When you reconnect to the website, the stored data is displayed again. The user data is not stored on the mychaletfinder.com servers at any time. To allow the storage of the Cookies you must enable these in your Internet software (browser). When filling in the booking or enquiry form you can indicate if you would like to receive information on current travel offers via the mychaletfinder.com newsletter when launched. When you no longer wish to receive such offers you can cancel the newsletter at any time without providing reasons.

Contacting Advertisers

The information that you enter into any of the forms we offer to allow you to contact property rental or property for sale advertisers is recorded by us and then sent to the advertiser that you chose to contact. This helps them provide you with a more personalised service. 

Email a Friend

When you use the email a friend feature of this Site we record which properties you have sent to the friend, solely so that we can track the popularity of those properties. We record the other details provided in the email for internal monitoring of the service. We will NOT add any information collected in this manner to our mailing lists or inform the advertiser, to protect you and the recipient's privacy.

Registering with us

If you register with us, we save the details you provide and use them to enable us to personalise the service we offer to you. You can update your details at any time via the website. When you are signed in, we automatically pre-populate your saved details on contact forms.

Saving properties

If you select a property as a "favourite", we can identify which properties you have selected. We may aggregate these details to indicate how many users have selected a property as a "favourite", but we will not make available to third parties any personal data relating to which users have selected a property as a "favourite". 

###  Who has access to the information you provide or we collect

We retain access to all personal information that we have collected from you.

We will not otherwise disclose, sell or distribute Your Information to any third party without your permission unless we are required to do so by law.

### Access to, changing or removing the information we hold

Registered users of this website can update their information, change settings or cancel their registration within their account settings once signed in.

Non-registered and registered users of this Site can request we provide them with a copy of the personally identifiable information we hold by contacting us. You may ask us to make any necessary changes to ensure that such information is accurate and kept up-to-date.

### Tracking & Analytics

#### Cookies and tracking

Like many websites, we use "cookies" to enable us to personalise your visits to this website, simplify the signing-in procedure, keep track of your preferences and to track the usage of this website. Cookies are small pieces of information that are stored in the hard drive of your computer by your browser. Your browser will have the option to prevent websites using cookies (your browser's help screen or manual will tell you how to do this), but please note that this may reduce the functionality of this Site and other websites.

Like all websites, our servers automatically record 'log files' containing information about the volume and characteristics of our website traffic e.g. IP address, numbers of pages viewed, length of time spent on site. We use log files to build pictures of how our site is used that help us to monitor and improve the service. We cannot identify you from your log files.

#### Google Analytics

This website uses Google Analytics, a web analytics service provided by Google, Inc. (“Google”). Google Analytics uses “cookies,” which are text files placed on your computer, to help the website analyze how users use the site. The information generated by the cookie about your use of the website will be transmitted to and stored by Google on servers in the United States. In case IP-anonymisation is activated on this Website, your IP address will be truncated within the area of Member States of the European Union or other parties to the Agreement on the European Economic Area. Only in exceptional cases the whole IP address will be first transferred to a Google server in the USA and truncated there. The IP-anonymisation is active on this Website. 

Google will use this information on behalf of the operator of this Website for the purpose of evaluating your use of the Website, compiling reports on Website activity for Website operators and providing them other services relating to Website activity and internet usage. The IP-address that your Browser conveys within the scope of Google Analytics will not be associated with any other data held by Google. You may refuse the use of cookies by selecting the appropriate settings on your browser, however please note that if you do this you may not be able to use the full functionality of this Website. You can also opt-out from being tracked by Google Analytics with effect for the future by downloading and installing Google Analytics Opt-out Browser Add-on for your current web browser:https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en.

### Security, storage and transfer of information

We follow strict security procedures to ensure that your personal information is not damaged, destroyed, or disclosed to a third party without your permission (unless they are providing services as outlined in the 'who has access to Your Information' section above) and to prevent unauthorised access to it. The computers that store the information are kept in a secure facility with restricted physical access and we use secure firewalls and other measures to restrict electronic access. If we are working with third parties we will require them to have in place similar measures to protect Your Information.

All of the information we collect or record is restricted to our offices. Only employees who need the information to perform a specific job are granted access to personally identifiable information. We will explicitly ask you when we need information to identify you. We may require you to co-operate with our security checks before we disclose information to you. You can update the personal information that you give us at any time by editing them in Your admin area of the website.

Your Information will not be transferred outside of the European Economic Area.

We will retain Your Information for a reasonable period or for as long as is required by law.

#### Property Information

Details held by us about a property do not comprise personal data as defined by the General Data Protection Regulations 2018. MyChaletFinder.com may use the data which we hold about properties advertised to provide professional valuation services and other data services to third parties. If your property is listed for sale or rent on MyChaletFinder.com you may ask us not to use some or all of the details of your property to provide such data services. In this event please email us at info@mychaletfinder.com stating your full name and address, confirmation that you are the owner of the property upon whose instructions we are entitled to act, the full postal address of your property, the date it was placed on the market for sale or rent, and the name address and telephone number of the agent you have instructed to market the property if applicable.

### Changes to the policy

We may change this policy from time to time as we add new services or features or in response to changes in the law or our commercial arrangements. Any changes to this policy will be posted on this Site.

### How to contact us

If you have any queries or comments about the policy, our use of your personal information or wish to unsubscribe from messages from us, please get in touch by emailing us at info@mychaletfinder.com or writing to us at Continental Traveller Limited, C/O Cloch Solicitors, Standard Buildings, 94 Hope street, Glasgow, G2 6PH
